Inventory of the Robert Arrowsmith papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Robert Arrowsmith papers
1914-1921
XX135
Hoover Institution Archives
4 oversized boxes, 4 envelopes (8.0 linear feet)
Correspondence, clippings, printed matter, memorabilia, and photographs relating to conditions in German-occupied Belgium during World War I, relief activities of the Commission for Relief in Belgium (CRB), and war loan and relief publicity in the United States.
Arrowsmith, Robert, 1860-1928.
Access
The collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Robert Arrowsmith (1860-1928) was an American from New Jersey who served as a member of the Commission for Relief in Belgium (CRB) during World War I, working in Belgium and campaigning for funds in the United States. Arrowsmith was in charge of the transportation and distribution of food supplies in the province of Liège during the war and in 1918 took up the clothing campaign of the CRB.
Scope and Content of Collection
The collection consists of photographs and four scrapbooks that contain correspondence, news clippings, maps, posters, photographs, ephemera, and CRB distribution orders and inventories, all of which relate to Arrowsmith's work with, and the relief activities of, the Commission for Relief in Belgium, the conditions in German-occupied Belgium during World War I, and war loan and relief publicity in the United States.
Related Collection(s)
Commission for Relief in Belgium Records, Hoover Institution Archives
Frederick H. Chatfield papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Commission for Relief in Belgium (1914-1930); Belgium--History--German occupation, 1914-1918.; International relief.; World War, 1914-1918--Belgium.; World War, 1914-1918--Civilian relief.; World War, 1914-1918--United States.
- Visual Materials, circa 1914-1918
  Scope and Contents note
  Consists of photographs, postcards, and illustrations depicting life in Belgium, the activities of the CRB, and the effects of World War I. Arranged by subject.
  - Photographs and postcards of King Albert I and Queen Elisabeth of Belgium and their children during World War I, circa 1914-1916 (Envelope A)
  - Photographs and postcards of war damage and scenes at the Western front during World War I, circa 1914-1918 (Envelope B)
  - Postcards and political cartoons relating to Belgium in World War I, circa 1915-1917 (Envelope C)
  - Small prints of CRB members, offices, and activities, circa 1914-1918 (Envelope D)
- Scrapbooks, 1914-1921
  Includes CRB service-related material such as distribution inventories, logs, correspondence, membership handbooks, maps, news clippings, posters, and other ephemera. Also included are postcards and photographs that reflect the CRB's efforts and the devastation to occupied Belgium. Arranged in chronological order.
  - 1914-1916 (Box 1)
  - 1915-1917 (Box 2)
  - 1916 (Box 3)
  - 1918-1921 (Box 4)